<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Epigraphy.info</title>
    <description>Epigraphy.info is an international open community pursuing a collaborative environment for digital epigraphy, which facilitates scholarly communication and interaction.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 21:13:18 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 21:13:18 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Membership form published</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;join-us&quot;&gt;Join us!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to be involved in the &lt;em&gt;Epigraphy.info&lt;/em&gt; community, please fill in the following form and we will get in touch with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/join_us/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Join us here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions to the members of the &lt;em&gt;Steering Committee&lt;/em&gt;, you can reach them via &lt;strong&gt;info@epigraphy.info&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wish to unsubscribe from all communications of the &lt;em&gt;Epigraphy.info&lt;/em&gt; community and revoke your membership, you can do so by contacting &lt;strong&gt;info@epigraphy.info&lt;/strong&gt; at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/22/Membership_form.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/22/Membership_form.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>social-media</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roman Inscriptions of Britain in Schools project launched</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;calling-all-roman-history-lovers-especially-teachers&quot;&gt;Calling all Roman history lovers, especially teachers!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have publicly launched the &lt;em&gt;Roman Inscriptions of Britain in Schools&lt;/em&gt; project. Our mission is to provide access for all to the diverse voices of Roman Britain and to encourage the teaching of classical subjects in schools through fascinating texts and objects. The project is a collaboration between the &lt;a href=&quot;https://latinnow.eu/&quot;&gt;LatinNow&lt;/a&gt; project and the educational charity &lt;a href=&quot;https://classicsforall.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Classics for All&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eagle-eyed users of &lt;a href=&quot;https://romaninscriptionsofbritain.org/&quot;&gt;Roman Inscriptions of Britain Online&lt;/a&gt; may already have spotted the website’s revamp, making it easier to navigate, and a new section for &lt;a href=&quot;https://romaninscriptionsofbritain.org/schools/&quot;&gt;schools&lt;/a&gt;. Phase 1 of the project has provided support for users with a video on ‘what are Roman inscriptions’, a ‘how to use’ section, a glossary for schools, plus a suite of materials for &lt;a href=&quot;https://romaninscriptionsofbritain.org/schools/age-groups/stage-2&quot;&gt;KS2&lt;/a&gt; which support local history studies through activities focused on the North, South, East and West of the country. We have also created &lt;a href=&quot;https://romaninscriptionsofbritain.org/schools/themes&quot;&gt;thematic pages&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;em&gt;childhood&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;migration&lt;/em&gt;, with &lt;em&gt;languages&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;education&lt;/em&gt; coming soon. In addition a selection of texts from the &lt;em&gt;Roman Inscriptions of Britain II&lt;/em&gt; volumes on non-stone epigraphy has been released, ahead of the full roll-out in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next phase of the project we will create bespoke materials for KS5. Please send feedback to ribschools@gmail.com, and tell us what you would like to see in future phases. You can find out more in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://latinnow.eu/2022/11/11/roman-inscriptions-of-britain-in-schools/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The LatinNow and Classics for All team&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/15/RIB_in_schools.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/15/RIB_in_schools.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>social-media</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Events form published</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;events-form-published&quot;&gt;Events form published!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to promote your event via the Epigraphy.info website and its social media?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Submit your event in the following form and the Social Media Team will do their best to advertise it online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/events/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Submit your event here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, let us know about your event well in advance, as any last minute requests will not be accommodated. All the applications will be reviewed by the Epigraphy.info Social Media Working Group before any publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions to the members of the &lt;strong&gt;Social Media team&lt;/strong&gt;, you can reach them via socialmedia@epigraphy.info.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/15/Event_form.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/15/Event_form.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>social-media</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Valete Viatores project publication as Open Access</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;valete-viatores-project-published-a-new-open-access-book&quot;&gt;Valete Viatores project published a new Open Access book&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Valete Viatores project&lt;/strong&gt; published on 7 October 2022 a book &lt;em&gt;Valete Vos Viatores: Travelling through Latin inscriptions across the Roman Empire&lt;/em&gt; as Open Access and available to download: http://monographs.uc.pt/iuc/catalog/book/295&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DOI:&lt;/strong&gt; https://doi.org/10.14195/978-989-26-2336-8&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords:&lt;/strong&gt; Epigraphy, Roman Epigraphy, epigraphic habit, epigraphic culture, digital Epigraphy, 3D Epigraphy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Synopsis:&lt;/strong&gt; Inscriptions were one of the trademarks of Romanization. Used as a real mass media, they covered almost all facets of Roman public and private life. Following common patterns, however, this habit of engraving inscriptions, the so-called “epigraphic habit”, took shape in different manifestations in each region, in each province, configuring diverse and attractive epigraphic cultures. This volume, the result of a Creative Europe project coordinated by the University of Navarra and with the participation of the University of Coimbra, the one at Bordeaux and La Sapienza in Roma and, also, of the Museo Nazionale Romano and different research centers in Portugal, France, Spain and Italy, reviews not only the functions of some of these inscriptions with new approaches to well-known repertoires but also the new tools that -from the rise of the Internet to the use of digital photogrammetry, from digital epigraphy to 3d epigraphy- are being implemented for their study, their understanding and, above all, the social dissemination of their values, builders, in large part, of European identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons &lt;strong&gt;Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/10/Valete_viatores.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/10/Valete_viatores.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>social-media</category>
        
        <category>partner-project</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First International Colloquium Comparative Epigraphy in October 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;first-international-colloquium-comparative-epigraphy&quot;&gt;First International Colloquium Comparative Epigraphy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Universitat de Barcelona, 28th – 30th September 2023&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;call-for-papers&quot;&gt;Call for Papers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research team LITTERA is happy to announce an international colloquium on Comparative
Epigraphy, to be held on the &lt;strong&gt;28th–30th of September 2023&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;Universitat de Barcelona&lt;/strong&gt;.
The comparative study –both genetic and typological– of written cultures is a still incipient but
very promising methodology. This colloquium aims to assess the potential contribution of a
Comparative Epigraphy to the analysis of the numerous written cultures that were generated,
developed and, in most cases, disappeared in the Mediterranean world between the first
millennium BC and the end of the Roman empire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The colloquium will be articulated around six thematic sections introduced by the following
lectures:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;J. Velaza: &lt;em&gt;Why Comparative Epigraphy?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I.-X. Adiego: &lt;em&gt;The written cultures of the Anatolian World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;M. G. Amadasi: &lt;em&gt;The written cultures of the Phoenician world&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;M. P. de Hoz: &lt;em&gt;The written cultures of the Greek world&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;P. Poccetti: &lt;em&gt;The written cultures of the Italian Peninsula&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;F. Beltrán: &lt;em&gt;The written cultures of the Iberian Peninsula&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We invite communication proposals that address both the theoretical aspects of the
methodology and studies on typologies, functions, media and epigraphic forms, as well as any
other type of contribution in which the comparative method predominates. Presentations will
be 20 minutes long, followed by 10 minutes for questions and discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you would like to present at the colloquium, please email an abstract of 750/1.000 words
and a short bio to epigrafiacomparada@gmail.com by the 31st of January 2023&lt;/strong&gt;. A scientific
committee will analyze the proposals and communicate their acceptance before &lt;strong&gt;20th of March
2023&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have further questions, please email &lt;strong&gt;epigrafiacomparada@gmail.com&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/09/CFP_comparative_epigraphy_Oct_2023.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/09/CFP_comparative_epigraphy_Oct_2023.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>social-media</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Save the date for the seventh Epigraphy.info workshop in April 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dear friends of Epigraphy.info&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to announce that the &lt;strong&gt;seventh Epigraphy.info workshop&lt;/strong&gt; will be taking place between &lt;em&gt;Monday April 24 and Wednesday April 26 2023 in Leuven&lt;/em&gt;. Please, &lt;strong&gt;save the date!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event will be held primarily as in-person meeting but we plan for some combination of a hybrid format for participants that would otherwise be prevented from attending.
More information about the venue, the registration and the programme will be available at Epigraphy.info website in late January 2023.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have an interesting project you would like to present at the conference, please contact the &lt;em&gt;Steering committee&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@epigraphy.info&quot;&gt;info@epigraphy.info&lt;/a&gt;) who is in charge of putting together a program of the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Steering Committee&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2022/10/27/Workshop_VII_Leuven_Save_the_date.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2022/10/27/Workshop_VII_Leuven_Save_the_date.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>social-media</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Epigrapy.info has its own YouTube Channel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After the &lt;strong&gt;6th Epigraphy.info workshop&lt;/strong&gt; the Social Media group created an account on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/EpigraphyInfo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YouTube&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. We are planning to share clips about epigraphy, databases and interviews with digital epigraphists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our very first video is showing the brilliant &lt;strong&gt;key lecture note given by Polly Low&lt;/strong&gt; during the workshop hosted by the IAS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more: Stay tuned and subscribe on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/EpigraphyInfo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YouTube&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Epigraphy.info_YouTube_Header.png&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; alt=&quot;Header of our YouTube channel&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2022/01/24/YouTube_Channel.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2022/01/24/YouTube_Channel.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>social-media</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Upcoming 6th Epigraphy.info workshop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear digital epigraphists!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce that the &lt;strong&gt;6th Epigraphy.info workshop&lt;/strong&gt; will be organised by The Institute for Advanced Study and will take place from &lt;strong&gt;October 20th-22nd, 2021&lt;/strong&gt;. Due to the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic, the workshop will be held &lt;strong&gt;online&lt;/strong&gt; over Zoom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information see &lt;a href=&quot;https://epigraphy.info/workshop_6/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2021/09/21/6th_Workshop.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2021/09/21/6th_Workshop.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DTS Hackathon's registration is open</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;register-for-dts-hackathon-and-win-a-prize&quot;&gt;Register for DTS Hackathon and win a prize&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(posted on behalf of Matteo Romanello and Pietro Liuzzo)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear colleagues,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we would like to remind you that registrations to the 1st online &lt;a href=&quot;https://distributed-text-services.github.io/workshops/events/2021-hackathon/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DTS Hackathon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are open until 24.09.2021 (for details, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://distributed-text-services.github.io/workshops/events/2021-hackathon/#registration&quot;&gt;registration page&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This hackathon – funded by the &lt;em&gt;dhCenter UNIL-EPFL and the École Nationale des Chartes&lt;/em&gt; – is open to DH researchers, research software developers / engineers, and more generally to anyone involved in writing code and software to publish texts online, in any language and from any period and area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;schedule&quot;&gt;Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hackathon will run fully online, and mostly asynchronously, between September 27 and October 10, 2021. A detailed schedule of the event can be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://distributed-text-services.github.io/workshops/events/2021-hackathon/#hackathon-schedule&quot;&gt;hackathon’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prizes&quot;&gt;Prizes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The  contributions developed during the hackathon will be evaluated by an international jury which will award prizes in four
 categories. Category winners will be awarded a prize of their choice between the two following options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://remarkable.com/store/remarkable-2&quot;&gt;Remarkable2 e-ink reader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.galaxus.ch/it/s1/product/sandisk-portable-ssd-2000gb-ssd-esterne-14967106&quot;&gt;Transkribus ScanTent + SanDisk portable SSD drive (1TB)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hack-ideas&quot;&gt;Hack ideas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who would like to join the hackathon but have not yet identified what to work on, we recommend you to keep an eye on the list of
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/distributed-text-services/workshops/labels/Hackathon&quot;&gt;hack ideas&lt;/a&gt; that are being put forward. If anything catches your attention you can get in touch with the proponent, start discussing it further and eventually form a team. All collected ideas will be pitched by their proponent(s) on the first day of the hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2021/09/20/DTS_hackathon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2021/09/20/DTS_hackathon.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Epigraphy.info has a new website!</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;valete-viatores-χαίρετε-παροδῖται&quot;&gt;Valete viatores! χαίρετε, παροδῖται!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce the launch of the new &lt;strong&gt;Epigraphy.info&lt;/strong&gt;  website!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Epigraphy_info_website_launch04.png&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; alt=&quot;Epigraphy.info launches a new website!&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you can read about the Epigraphy.info community, access information about past and future activities and meetings, and get to know individual working groups and their current aims. Most importantly, if you would like to become part of the community, you can &lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;get in touch directly with us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to to stay abreast of the latest developments in Digital Epigraphy, you can follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/epigraphy.info/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/epigraphy_info&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/epigraphy.info/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in the technology behind the scene, the new website is built on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; the infrastructure, stored at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/epigraphy-info&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Epigraphy-info GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, which will make the site more dynamic and collaborative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
/contact/
--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2021/04/20/Official_launch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2021/04/20/Official_launch.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>website</category>
        
        <category>social-media</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
