<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Epigraphy.info</title>
    <description>Epigraphy.info is an international open community pursuing a collaborative environment for digital epigraphy, which facilitates scholarly communication and interaction.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 16:28:33 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 16:28:33 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Call for papers Workshop on Machine Learning for Ancient Languages</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;1st-cfp-workshop-on-machine-learning-for-ancient-languages-ml4al-acl-2024&quot;&gt;1st CfP: Workshop on Machine Learning for Ancient Languages (ML4AL) @ACL 2024&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the Organising Committee, it is my pleasure to circulate the 1st &lt;em&gt;Call for Papers for the Workshop on Machine Learning for Ancient Languages (ML4AL 2024).&lt;/em&gt;
The Workshop is co-located at ACL 2024 and will take place in a &lt;strong&gt;hybrid format in Bangkok, Thailand and remotely, on 15 August 2024.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The submission deadline is May 17th, 2024 11:59pm, UTC-12 (anywhere on Earth).
Please refer to the ML4AL workshop website &lt;a href=&quot;http://ml4al.com&quot;&gt;http://ml4al.com&lt;/a&gt; for the full CfP and for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DESCRIPTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technological aids have long supported the study of ancient texts, but in recent years advances in Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML) have enabled analyses on Ancient Languages on an unprecedented scale and in unparalleled detail. The ML4AL Workshop aims to inspire collaboration and support research momentum in the emerging field of ML for the study of ancient texts. We invite contributions tackling texts from the diverse corners of the globe, in any language, script or medium. We establish a chronological scope from the inception of writing systems in ancient Mesopotamia and Egypt (3400 BCE) to the late first millennium CE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome contributions on topics related to, but not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Digitization: bringing textual sources to a high-quality machine-readable format (e.g., through HTR).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restoration: recovering missing text and reassembling fragmented written artefacts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attribution: contextualising a document within its original geographical, chronological and authorial setting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linguistic analysis: involving tasks such as POS tagging, text parsing, segmentation, representation learning, semantics, sentiment, language identification.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Textual criticism: the process of reconstructing a text’s philological tradition of textual transmission, including the tasks of stemmatology and intertextuality.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Translation and decipherment: which aim to make a text’s language comprehensible and interpretable to modern-day researchers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encompassing such a vast and fertile remit for ML applications, the ML4AL Workshop is designed to facilitate and invigorate the ongoing collaborative impetus between ML and the Humanities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2024.aclweb.org/&quot;&gt;ACL&lt;/a&gt; is the most prominent conference on ML and NLP in the world, and this is the first time a workshop on the topic of ML for Ancient Languages is included at an ACL meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We particularly welcome submissions which tackle low-data, underrepresented, non-Western ancient languages, and we encourage researchers and practitioners from diverse backgrounds, working on ancient languages, irrespective of their gender, ethnicity, nationality, or academic affiliations, including fellows tackling low-underrepresented and non-Western centric ancient languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SUBMISSION INFORMATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome long (8 page) and short (4 page) paper submissions, in PDF format following the ACL template style, made through OpenReview or ARR.
Accepted regular workshop papers will be included in the workshop proceedings, but non-archival submissions are also welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All submissions should be completely anonymous to allow a double-blind review process (each paper is expected to be reviewed by at least three reviewers). Selected accepted papers will be presented orally and the rest as posters. Papers on relevant topics that have appeared or might appear in other venues (workshops, conferences, journals) are also welcome, which can be presented at the workshop but will not be included in the workshop proceedings. Already published contributions (excluding preprints) cannot be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ORGANISING COMMITTEE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr John Pavlopoulos, Athens University of Economics and Business, Greece
Dr Thea Sommerschield, University of Nottingham, UK
Dr Yannis Assael, Google DeepMind, UK
Dr Shai Gordin, Ariel University, Israel
Prof. Kyunghyun Cho, NYU, CIFAR, Genentech, USA
Prof. Marco Passarotti, Università Cattolica del Sacro Cuore, Italy
Dr Rachele Sprugnoli, Università di Parma, Italy
Dr Yudong Liu, Western Washington University, USA
Dr Bin Li, Nanjing Normal University, China
Dr Adam Anderson, UC Berkeley, USA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact the organisers at: &lt;strong&gt;ml4al.organizers@gmail.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROGRAM COMMITTEE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Masayuki Asahara; John Bodel; Gregory Crane; Katrien De Graef; Sanhong Deng; Mark Depauw; Hanne Eckhoff; Margherita Fantoli; Minxuan Feng; Ethan Fetaya; Federica Gamba; Laura Hawkins; Chul Heo; Petra Heřmánková; Marietta Horster; Renfen Hu; Kyle Johnson; Alek Keersmaekers; Ussen Kimanuka; Thomas Koentges; Els Lefever; Chaya Liebeskind; Eliese-Sophia Lincke; Chao-Lin Liu; Liu Liu; Congjun Long; Jiaming Luo; Massimo Maiocchi; Isabelle Marthot-Santaniello; Barbara McGillivray; M. Willis Monroe; Alex Mullen; Chiara Palladino; Chanjun Park, Upstage; Edoardo M. Ponti; Mladen Popovic; Jonathan Prag; Avital Romach; Edgar Roman-Rangel; Matteo Romanello; Brent Seales; Andrew Senior; Si Shen; Barak Sober; Richard Sproat; Gabriel Stanovsky; Vanessa Stefanak; Silvia Stopponi; Qi Su; Matthew I. Swindall; Xuri Tang; Charlotte Tupman; Dongbo Wang; Haneul Yoo; Chongsheng Zhang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT DATES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paper submission deadline: &lt;strong&gt;May 17, 2024&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Notification of acceptance: &lt;strong&gt;June 17, 2024&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Camera-ready paper due: &lt;strong&gt;July 1, 2024&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Workshop: &lt;strong&gt;August 15, 2024&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All deadlines are 11:59 pm UTC -12h (“anywhere on Earth”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much, and apologies for cross-posting!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2024/02/20/CFP_ML4AL_workshop.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2024/02/20/CFP_ML4AL_workshop.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>social-media</category>
        
        <category>cfp</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Call for papers and posters for the eighth Epigraphy.info workshop in April 2024</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dear friends of Epigraphy.info&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The eighth Epigraphy.info workshop will take place in &lt;strong&gt;Berlin (Germany)&lt;/strong&gt;, from &lt;strong&gt;3-5 April 2024&lt;/strong&gt;, hosted by the &lt;em&gt;Department of Digital History at the Humboldt University of Berlin&lt;/em&gt;, and with the courtesy of the &lt;em&gt;Berlin-Brandenburg Academy of Sciences and Humanities (BBAW)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are planning an &lt;strong&gt;open meeting&lt;/strong&gt; to discuss and try different tools related to Digital Epigraphy. If you are already part of the Epigraphy.info community or just interested in Digital Epigraphy, we warmly invite you to come to our meeting in Berlin. During the workshop, we will explain the objectives and expectations of Epigraphy.info and invite new members to get involved. The meeting is ideally planned as an in-person event, especially to present a paper or poster, but you can attend and discuss remotely. We might record some of the presentations and talks and later make them available via the Epigraphy.info Youtube channel and place the posters on the Epigraphy.info website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meeting will include &lt;strong&gt;presentations&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;training sessions&lt;/strong&gt;. Part of it will be related to current Digital Epigraphy projects worldwide and we encourage scholars who work on Digital Epigraphy to present proposals adapted to a wide variety of formats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panels&lt;/strong&gt; for those scholars who want to discuss a topic or have a specific agenda. We will provide space to promote academic discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Papers&lt;/strong&gt; for scholars who want to present their project or results of a Project Research.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Posters&lt;/strong&gt; to present news, education projects, updates on existing projects etc.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hands-on sessions&lt;/strong&gt;. We are exploring different options such as hackathons, and presentations of a new tool followed by training (20 minutes presentation + 20 minutes training). If a group thinks it would be useful for the community, we encourage to present a proposal. If you would like to provide more extended training, please, reach out, so we can accommodate you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those interested, please send your abstract (around 200 words for papers and posters, 400 words for panels and hands-on sessions) before November 30th to the Steering Committee at info@epigraphy.info. We will notify selected participants and circulate a provisional program by the end of December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Steering Committee of Epigraphy.info&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2023/10/16/Workshop_VIII_Berlin_CFP.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2023/10/16/Workshop_VIII_Berlin_CFP.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>social-media</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Release of the EDEp editor for active testing</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;release-of-the-edep-editor-for-active-testing&quot;&gt;Release of the EDEp editor for active testing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear community of Epigraphy.info,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are glad to finally release the EDEp editor for active testing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://edep.adw.uni-heidelberg.de&quot;&gt;https://edep.adw.uni-heidelberg.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the section &lt;em&gt;‘Demo’&lt;/em&gt; you will find examples of editions provided by us. In the section ‘Workspace’ you can create and save new entries in order to refer to them in your feedback. Note: you need to be logged in to save. The login credentials are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Username:&lt;/strong&gt; edep&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Password:&lt;/strong&gt; edep&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please test strictly, realistically and thoroughly as if you wanted to use the editor for your specific work. The testing period will last from today up to and including July 24th 2023. The duration of the test phase is deliberately kept manageable in order to enable concentrated and intensive testing before the summer break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suggestions for improvement and queries are kindly requested to this email address: edep-test@exist-db.org&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you all in advance for your cooperation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David, Francisca, Jörn, Marietta, and Wolfgang&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 05:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2023/07/06/EDEP_editor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2023/07/06/EDEP_editor.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NACGLE IV 2024 - call for papers</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;call-for-papers-for-the-fourth-north-american-congress-of-greek-and-latin-epigraphy-nacgle-iv&quot;&gt;Call for Papers for the Fourth North American Congress of Greek and Latin Epigraphy (NACGLE IV)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;University of Chicago, January 8-9, 2024&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Epigraphy and Public Life in the Graeco-Roman World&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Fourth North American Congress of Greek and Latin Epigraphy (NACGLE IV)&lt;/strong&gt; will be held
at the &lt;strong&gt;University of Chicago&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;January 8-9, 2024&lt;/strong&gt;, under the aegis of the American Society of Greek
and Latin Epigraphy (ASGLE), and with support from the University of Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The congress will take place at the Oriental Institute on the campus of the University of Chicago and
will be held immediately following the Annual Meeting of the Archaeological Institute of America and
the Society for Classical Studies in Chicago (January 4-7, 2024). It will include thematic panels on a
variety of topics, a poster session, a keynote lecture followed by a reception. We are hoping to organize
a visit to the Oriental Institute Museum during the congress. Please note that the conference will be in-
person and on-site in Chicago only. Remote participation will not be possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We invite papers that discuss the contribution of epigraphy to our understanding of the political, civic,
economic and social life and institutions of the Greek and Roman world from the archaic period through
late antiquity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Papers may be devoted to the importance of epigraphy for our understanding of any of the following
topics: civic, political and legal activity; economic production and exchange; social hierarchies and
social mobility; rural communities and agrarian life; military communities. Sessions at the congress will
also be devoted to discussions of new inscriptions and new techniques for reading epigraphic texts and
analyzing inscriptions in bulk. A separate &lt;strong&gt;Call for Posters&lt;/strong&gt; will be circulated in spring 2023.
The congress Organizing Committee is pleased to invite individual &lt;strong&gt;abstracts&lt;/strong&gt; for the parallel sessions.
They should be a maximum of 500 words (bibliography excluded), suitable for a 20-minute
presentation. Abstracts of between 350 and 500 words should be submitted by email attachment in PDF
or Word document format by &lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 15 April 2023&lt;/strong&gt; to NACGLE2024@gmail.com. (Poster
proposals will have a later submission date.) Abstracts will be reviewed by members of the congress
Organizing Committee, and the results of the review process will be made known to potential
participants soon thereafter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panels:&lt;/strong&gt; The Organizing Committee also invites proposals for panels. Panels should consist of three or
four papers. The panel organizer should submit all abstracts of a maximum of 500 words each
(bibliography excluded), along with a summary of the panel. This summary should include the names of
the presenters, their affiliation and email addresses, and the titles of the papers, as well as a statement of
the significance of the theme and the theoretical and/or methodological approaches to be applied. When
submitting a summary for the panel, please include the term “panel session NACGLE 2024” in the
subject heading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To submit a proposal, it is not necessary to be a current member of ASGLE, but we hope that all those
whose papers are accepted for presentation in Chicago will join ASGLE, if they are not already
members.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2023/03/07/NACGLE2024_cfp.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2023/03/07/NACGLE2024_cfp.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>7th Epigraphy.info workshop - preliminary programme</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear members of the Epigraphy.info community,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 24-26 April 2023 the &lt;strong&gt;7th Epigraphy.info workshop&lt;/strong&gt; will take place in Leuven (at the campus of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arts.kuleuven.be/english/contact&quot;&gt;KU Leuven’s Faculty of Arts&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday April 24th, selected participants will be able to attend 2 hands-on &lt;strong&gt;training sessions&lt;/strong&gt; (in collaboration with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://site.unibo.it/encode/en&quot;&gt;ENCODE project&lt;/a&gt;) on the application of EpiDoc (with a focus on Mycenean inscriptions) and the use of the READ (Research Environment for Ancient Documents) platform for epigraphy. The afternoon session will be followed by a &lt;strong&gt;poster session&lt;/strong&gt; (including a reception, at 16:30 CET). If you would be interested in presenting your digital epigraphy work in this format, please send a title and a short abstract to info@epigraphy.info (&lt;strong&gt;deadline: March 24th&lt;/strong&gt;). By March 31st, you will receive a notification from the committee whether your poster proposal has been accepted. We will also offer the possibility to present your poster virtually, and during the workshop the posters will also be displayed on the Epigraphy.info website (where they can be published publicly afterwards).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Epigraphy.info workshop&lt;/strong&gt; (25-26 April) will be organized in a hybrid way and can therefore be attended online (at least all public sessions) as well as in-person. During the workshop, members of the different &lt;strong&gt;working groups&lt;/strong&gt; (on the Epigraphic Ontologies, Vocabularies, Outreach, Ethics, Social Media, etc.) will convene to interactively discuss their progress with the community. On Tuesday April 25th, a &lt;strong&gt;keynote lecture&lt;/strong&gt; will be followed by an (optional) &lt;strong&gt;social dinner&lt;/strong&gt;. The morning session on Wednesday April 26th will be dedicated to the &lt;strong&gt;future perspectives&lt;/strong&gt; of Epigraphy.info, including &lt;strong&gt;community decisions&lt;/strong&gt; on new steering committee members and the organization of the next Epigraphy.info workshop (applications are welcome at info@epigraphy.info). In the afternoon, the organization is preparing a &lt;strong&gt;social event&lt;/strong&gt;, in the form of a visit to a Belgian museum (including a small epigraphic collection).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would like to encourage both experienced and early career scholars to actively participate in this event. Therefore, we are offering the opportunity to present your work in the field of digital epigraphy. If you would be interested in giving a short presentation during the event, please contact the steering committee (&lt;strong&gt;deadline: February 26th&lt;/strong&gt;) via info@epigraphy.info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;registration-deadline-march-31st&quot;&gt;Registration (deadline: March 31st)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forms.gle/kvWaJKFWsBjqh3A47&quot;&gt;https://forms.gle/kvWaJKFWsBjqh3A47&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preliminary-program-check-for-updates&quot;&gt;Preliminary program (check for updates)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://epigraphy.info/workshop_7/&quot;&gt;https://epigraphy.info/workshop_7/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best wishes,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Epigraphy.info Steering Committee&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2023/02/17/Workshop_VII_preliminary_programme.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2023/02/17/Workshop_VII_preliminary_programme.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcemen</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Membership form published</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;join-us&quot;&gt;Join us!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to be involved in the &lt;em&gt;Epigraphy.info&lt;/em&gt; community, please fill in the following form and we will get in touch with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/join_us/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Join us here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions to the members of the &lt;em&gt;Steering Committee&lt;/em&gt;, you can reach them via &lt;strong&gt;info@epigraphy.info&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wish to unsubscribe from all communications of the &lt;em&gt;Epigraphy.info&lt;/em&gt; community and revoke your membership, you can do so by contacting &lt;strong&gt;info@epigraphy.info&lt;/strong&gt; at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/22/Membership_form.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/22/Membership_form.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>social-media</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roman Inscriptions of Britain in Schools project launched</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;calling-all-roman-history-lovers-especially-teachers&quot;&gt;Calling all Roman history lovers, especially teachers!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have publicly launched the &lt;em&gt;Roman Inscriptions of Britain in Schools&lt;/em&gt; project. Our mission is to provide access for all to the diverse voices of Roman Britain and to encourage the teaching of classical subjects in schools through fascinating texts and objects. The project is a collaboration between the &lt;a href=&quot;https://latinnow.eu/&quot;&gt;LatinNow&lt;/a&gt; project and the educational charity &lt;a href=&quot;https://classicsforall.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Classics for All&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eagle-eyed users of &lt;a href=&quot;https://romaninscriptionsofbritain.org/&quot;&gt;Roman Inscriptions of Britain Online&lt;/a&gt; may already have spotted the website’s revamp, making it easier to navigate, and a new section for &lt;a href=&quot;https://romaninscriptionsofbritain.org/schools/&quot;&gt;schools&lt;/a&gt;. Phase 1 of the project has provided support for users with a video on ‘what are Roman inscriptions’, a ‘how to use’ section, a glossary for schools, plus a suite of materials for &lt;a href=&quot;https://romaninscriptionsofbritain.org/schools/age-groups/stage-2&quot;&gt;KS2&lt;/a&gt; which support local history studies through activities focused on the North, South, East and West of the country. We have also created &lt;a href=&quot;https://romaninscriptionsofbritain.org/schools/themes&quot;&gt;thematic pages&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;em&gt;childhood&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;migration&lt;/em&gt;, with &lt;em&gt;languages&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;education&lt;/em&gt; coming soon. In addition a selection of texts from the &lt;em&gt;Roman Inscriptions of Britain II&lt;/em&gt; volumes on non-stone epigraphy has been released, ahead of the full roll-out in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next phase of the project we will create bespoke materials for KS5. Please send feedback to ribschools@gmail.com, and tell us what you would like to see in future phases. You can find out more in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://latinnow.eu/2022/11/11/roman-inscriptions-of-britain-in-schools/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The LatinNow and Classics for All team&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/15/RIB_in_schools.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/15/RIB_in_schools.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>social-media</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Events form published</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;events-form-published&quot;&gt;Events form published!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to promote your event via the Epigraphy.info website and its social media?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Submit your event in the following form and the Social Media Team will do their best to advertise it online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/events/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Submit your event here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, let us know about your event well in advance, as any last minute requests will not be accommodated. All the applications will be reviewed by the Epigraphy.info Social Media Working Group before any publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions to the members of the &lt;strong&gt;Social Media team&lt;/strong&gt;, you can reach them via socialmedia@epigraphy.info.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/15/Event_form.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/15/Event_form.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>social-media</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Valete Viatores project publication as Open Access</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;valete-viatores-project-published-a-new-open-access-book&quot;&gt;Valete Viatores project published a new Open Access book&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Valete Viatores project&lt;/strong&gt; published on 7 October 2022 a book &lt;em&gt;Valete Vos Viatores: Travelling through Latin inscriptions across the Roman Empire&lt;/em&gt; as Open Access and available to download: http://monographs.uc.pt/iuc/catalog/book/295&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DOI:&lt;/strong&gt; https://doi.org/10.14195/978-989-26-2336-8&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords:&lt;/strong&gt; Epigraphy, Roman Epigraphy, epigraphic habit, epigraphic culture, digital Epigraphy, 3D Epigraphy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Synopsis:&lt;/strong&gt; Inscriptions were one of the trademarks of Romanization. Used as a real mass media, they covered almost all facets of Roman public and private life. Following common patterns, however, this habit of engraving inscriptions, the so-called “epigraphic habit”, took shape in different manifestations in each region, in each province, configuring diverse and attractive epigraphic cultures. This volume, the result of a Creative Europe project coordinated by the University of Navarra and with the participation of the University of Coimbra, the one at Bordeaux and La Sapienza in Roma and, also, of the Museo Nazionale Romano and different research centers in Portugal, France, Spain and Italy, reviews not only the functions of some of these inscriptions with new approaches to well-known repertoires but also the new tools that -from the rise of the Internet to the use of digital photogrammetry, from digital epigraphy to 3d epigraphy- are being implemented for their study, their understanding and, above all, the social dissemination of their values, builders, in large part, of European identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons &lt;strong&gt;Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/10/Valete_viatores.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/10/Valete_viatores.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>social-media</category>
        
        <category>partner-project</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First International Colloquium Comparative Epigraphy in October 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;first-international-colloquium-comparative-epigraphy&quot;&gt;First International Colloquium Comparative Epigraphy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Universitat de Barcelona, 28th – 30th September 2023&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;call-for-papers&quot;&gt;Call for Papers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research team LITTERA is happy to announce an international colloquium on Comparative
Epigraphy, to be held on the &lt;strong&gt;28th–30th of September 2023&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;Universitat de Barcelona&lt;/strong&gt;.
The comparative study –both genetic and typological– of written cultures is a still incipient but
very promising methodology. This colloquium aims to assess the potential contribution of a
Comparative Epigraphy to the analysis of the numerous written cultures that were generated,
developed and, in most cases, disappeared in the Mediterranean world between the first
millennium BC and the end of the Roman empire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The colloquium will be articulated around six thematic sections introduced by the following
lectures:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;J. Velaza: &lt;em&gt;Why Comparative Epigraphy?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I.-X. Adiego: &lt;em&gt;The written cultures of the Anatolian World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;M. G. Amadasi: &lt;em&gt;The written cultures of the Phoenician world&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;M. P. de Hoz: &lt;em&gt;The written cultures of the Greek world&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;P. Poccetti: &lt;em&gt;The written cultures of the Italian Peninsula&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;F. Beltrán: &lt;em&gt;The written cultures of the Iberian Peninsula&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We invite communication proposals that address both the theoretical aspects of the
methodology and studies on typologies, functions, media and epigraphic forms, as well as any
other type of contribution in which the comparative method predominates. Presentations will
be 20 minutes long, followed by 10 minutes for questions and discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you would like to present at the colloquium, please email an abstract of 750/1.000 words
and a short bio to epigrafiacomparada@gmail.com by the 31st of January 2023&lt;/strong&gt;. A scientific
committee will analyze the proposals and communicate their acceptance before &lt;strong&gt;20th of March
2023&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have further questions, please email &lt;strong&gt;epigrafiacomparada@gmail.com&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/09/CFP_comparative_epigraphy_Oct_2023.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2022/11/09/CFP_comparative_epigraphy_Oct_2023.html</guid>
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
        <category>social-media</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
